$REQ_modname	Requiem 5.2.2 - "The Gathering Storm"
$REQ_modname_skills	Requiem - Skills Menu
$REQ_iHoursToRespawnCell	Cell respawn time
$REQ_iHoursToRespawnCell_highlight	This defines the time which is required to pass before a cell will respawn. Keep in mind that entering the cell resets the timer.
$REQ_iHoursToRespawnCell_slider	{0}days
$REQ_iHoursToRespawnCellCleared	Cleared cell respawn time
$REQ_iHoursToRespawnCellCleared_highlight	This defines the time which is required to pass before a cell marked as cleared will respawn. Keep in mind that entering the cell resets the timer.
$REQ_iHoursToRespawnCellCleared_slider	{0}days
$REQ_REQ_Combat_NoDeathHandling	Death Handling Vanilla Style
$REQ_REQ_Combat_NoDeathHandling_highlight	Using the autoload/quickload options yields the risk to corrupt game data.  By default Requiem therefore shows you an infinite death screen and you must load a save manually.
$REQ_fDiffMultHPByPCL	Difficulty - Damage dealt
$REQ_fDiffMultHPByPCL_highlight	This setting determines how much damage you deal with your attacks, use this instead of the main menu's difficulty bar to adjust the combat difficulty to your liking. [Disabling the difficulty bar is merely a safety precaution to prevent new players from experiencing a too easy or hard Requiem.]
$REQ_fDiffMultHPByPCL_slider	{0}%
$REQ_fDiffMultHPToPCL	Difficulty - Damage taken
$REQ_fDiffMultHPToPCL_highlight	This setting determines how much damage you take from attacks, use this instead of the main menu's difficulty bar to adjust the combat difficulty to your liking. [Disabling the difficulty bar is merely a safety precaution to prevent new players from experiencing a too easy or hard Requiem.]
$REQ_fDiffMultHPToPCL_slider	{0}%
$REQ_WIWaitDragon	Dragon random spawn interval
$REQ_WIWaitDragon_slider	{0} days
$REQ_WIWaitDragon_highlight	This setting determines the minimal time that needs to pass between two consecutive random dragon spawns.
$REQ_fPlayerHealthHeartbeatSlow	Heartbeat threshold
$REQ_fPlayerHealthHeartbeatSlow_highlight	This threshold defines when the heartbeat sound begins to notify you about your wounds. If you do not want the heartbeat at all, set the value to 0%.
$REQ_fPlayerHealthHeartbeatSlow_slider	{0}%
$REQ_fJumpHeightMin	Jump Height Factor
$REQ_fJumpHeightMin_highlight	This factor determines how high your character can jump.
$REQ_fJumpHeightMin_slider	{0}%
$REQ_REQ_Skills_RateFactor	Skillrate Factor
$REQ_REQ_Skills_RateFactor_slider	{0}%
$REQ_REQ_Skills_RateFactor_highlight	This options adjusts your experience gained for using any of your skills by the given factor.
$REQ_TimeScale	Timescale
$REQ_TimeScale_slider	1:{0}
$REQ_TimeScale_highlight	This value determines the ratio between real-time and game-time. By default, one real-time minute corresponds to 10 ingame minutes in Requiem.
$REQ_REQ_Debug_ArmorTraining	Armor Training Debug Mode
$REQ_REQ_Debug_ArmorTraining_highlight	If you suspect that the granted armor experience for wandering around is calculated incorrectly, you can activate this debug mode to see which pieces of equipment contribute.
$REQ_REQ_Compatibility_AttackSpeed	Attack Speed Dummy deactivated
$REQ_REQ_Compatibility_AttackSpeed_highlight	Requiem uses an 'Attack Speed Dummy' to allow for stacking attack speed buffs. If a second mod does the same, you can use this option to disable the one from Requiem to prevent superfast attacks.
$REQ_REQ_Combat_NoDragonFear	Dragons cause no fear
$REQ_REQ_Combat_NoDragonFear_highlight	Dragons have an aura of fear, which makes most NPCs flee in panic, excluding city guards and your followers. This option can be used to disable this aura.
$REQ_REQ_Combat_EssentialAgain	Essential Actors invincible
$REQ_REQ_Combat_EssentialAgain_highlight	This option restores the death-protection from the essential flag for actors. [Note that a few actors are immune to the killing effect anyway, since Skyrim has two different mechanims for being essential, of which only one can be easily circumvented.]
$REQ_REQ_Combat_NoOnHitDisarm	Exhaustion does not disarm
$REQ_REQ_Combat_NoOnHitDisarm_highlight	Usually, each enemy attack has a chance to disarm you, if you are out of stamina. With this option you can disable this feature.
$REQ_REQ_Atmosphere_AllowFastTravel	Fast Travel Allowed
$REQ_REQ_Atmosphere_AllowFastTravel_highlight	If this setting is enabled, you can use the fast travel mechanism, which is usually disabled by Requiem.
$REQ_REQ_Combat_NoFearAndYield	Fearless and steadfast enemies
$REQ_REQ_Combat_NoFearAndYield_highlight	Requiem features a Fear&Yield system, to deliver a more realistic approach to the yielding from Vanilla Skyrim. This option can be used to disable this feature.
$REQ_REQ_Debug_OnHit	Impact Effects Debug Mode
$REQ_REQ_Debug_OnHit_highlight	If you encounter impact effects (magicka/stamina drain, stagger, breaking bows, disarm) when they should not be there you can use this debug mode to trace back the source of the impact. Beware of concentration spells, they generate a lot of impact events and therefore message boxes in a short time.
$REQ_REQ_Combat_NoHorseTrample	No non-hostile Bull Rush/Trample
$REQ_REQ_Combat_NoHorseTrample_highlight	This options restricts trample and bull rush attacks such that they only affect actors that are already hostile to you.
$REQ_REQ_Atmosphere_NoPoisonISM	Poisons without visual effects
$REQ_REQ_Atmosphere_NoPoisonISM_highlight	This option disables the image space modifiers for poison and disease effects. Note that poison and disease resistance reduce the intensity of the visual distortions caused by poisons and diseases or even negate them completely.
$REQ_REQ_Skills_HideClutterRecipes	Recycling is not allowed
$REQ_REQ_Skills_HideClutterRecipes_highlight	While active, this options hides all crafting options which convert equipment and clutter items back into ingots.
$REQ_REQ_Atmosphere_SlowerHorses	Slower Horses
$REQ_REQ_Atmosphere_SlowerHorses_highlight	This option decreases the speed of all horses by about 25%.
$REQ_REQ_Skills_NoSmithingBooks	Smithing books non-mandatory
$REQ_REQ_Skills_NoSmithingBooks_highlight	If this option is active, you can choose smithing perks without having the corresponding crafting manual in your inventory.
$REQ_REQ_Debug_ExhaustionReset	Stamina Drain Reset (Exhaustion)
$REQ_REQ_Debug_ExhaustionReset_highlight	Checking this setting will reset your stamina drains if they freaked out. Just check this option, then leave the menu and everything should be fine again.
$REQ_REQ_Atmosphere_VampireRandomCarnage	Vampires raid randomly
$REQ_REQ_Atmosphere_VampireRandomCarnage_highlight	If this option is enabled, vampires will start random raids on villages and towns again, as they did in the original Dawnguard questline.
$REQ_cat_0	Combat
$REQ_cat_1	Skills & Perks
$REQ_cat_2	Atmosphere
$REQ_cat_3	Compability & Debug
$REQ_MarksmanPowerMod	ranged weapons
$REQ_MarksmanPowerMod_highlight	Your finesse with bows and crossbows is determined mostly by your stamina, with a minor contribution from your health.
$REQ_CarryWeight	carry weight
$REQ_CarryWeight_highlight	Your carry weight is dominated by your health, with a minor contribution from your stamina.
$REQ_cat_skill0	Secondary Attributes
$REQ_cat_skill0_header	Secondary Attributes Overview
$REQ_cat_skill1	Derived Attributes
$REQ_cat_skill1_header	Derived Attributes - Bonuses on Secondary Attributes
$REQ_Debug_ExhaustionReset_popup	Please leave the MCM now to finish the Stamina Drain reset.
$REQ_DiseaseResist	disease resistance
$REQ_DiseaseResist_bonus_highlight	Your natural disease resistance is governed by your stamina, with a moderate contribution from your health.
$REQ_DiseaseResist_highlight	Your disease resistance protects you from infections with diseases, which are often passed on by animals.
$REQ_ElectricResist	shock resistance
$REQ_ElectricResist_highlight	Shock resistance reduces all damage taken from electrical discharges.
$REQ_FireResist	fire resistance
$REQ_FireResist_highlight	Fire resistance protects from harm caused by any fires, regardless of their origin.
$REQ_FrostResist	frost resistance
$REQ_FrostResist_highlight	Frost resistance allows you to overcome death's cold embrace, be it of natural or magical origin.
$REQ_HealRateMult	health regeneration rate
$REQ_HealRateMult_highlight	Having health regeneration will allow your wounds to heal naturally without the application of medicine. (The value is given in percent of your current maximum health.)
$REQ_MagickaRateMult	magicka regeneration rate
$REQ_MagickaRateMult_bonus_highlight	Your magicka regeneration is governed only by your magicka.
$REQ_MagickaRateMult_highlight	The higher your magicka regeneration, the faster you will recover from the exertions of spellcasting. (The value is given in percent of your current maximum magicka.)
$REQ_MagicResist	magic resistance
$REQ_MagicResist_bonus_highlight	Your natural resistance against magic is solely determined by your magicka.
$REQ_MagicResist_highlight	Magical resistance allows you to withstand effects from all magical sources, be it an incoming fireball or a paralysis spell.
$REQ_MassPenalty	effective mass
$REQ_MassPenalty_highlight	The effective mass describes how much you are hampered by weight, mostly of your worn equipment. A value of 1.0 means no penalties. The larger the value becomes, the more severe your penalties on movement speed, stamina consumption, movement noises and casting costs will be.
$REQ_MassTotal	total mass
$REQ_MassTotal_highlight	The heavier your character is, the more likely you are to resist knockdown attacks, and the more likely your own knockdown attacks are to succeed. This value is mainly determined by the weight of your worn equipment.
$REQ_MovementNoiseMult	movement noises
$REQ_MovementNoiseMult_highlight	The heavier your worn equipment, the more noises you will make while sneaking around. (This value indicates how your movement noises, which are governed by your sneak skill, are amplified/muffled by your equipment and magic effects.)
$REQ_OneHandedPowerMod	one-handed weapons
$REQ_OneHandedPowerMod_highlight	Your finesse with one-handed weapons is determined by your health and stamina in equal parts.
$REQ_overviewheader_0	resistances
$REQ_overviewheader_1	regeneration rates
$REQ_overviewheader_2	movement
$REQ_overviewheader_3	mass
$REQ_persec	per second
$REQ_PoisonResist	poison resistance
$REQ_PoisonResist_bonus_highlight	Your natural poison resistance is governed by your health, with a moderate contribution from your stamina.
$REQ_PoisonResist_highlight	Your poison resistance allows you to overcome all kinds of poisons, be they man-made or natural. You may shrug off the effects from a bandit's poisoned blade as well as the toxic spit of a chaurus or the venomous bite of a frostbite spider.
$REQ_skillheader_0	resistances
$REQ_skillheader_1	regeneration and conditioning
$REQ_skillheader_2	damage
$REQ_skillheader_3	thu'um mastery
$REQ_SpeedMult	movement speed
$REQ_SpeedMult_bonus_highlight	Your movement speed is dominated by your stamina, with a minor contribution from your health.
$REQ_SpeedMult_highlight	The lighter your worn equipment and the better your constitution is, the faster you can run. (This value is relative to the base speed for humanoids.)
$REQ_StaminaRateMult	stamina regeneration rate
$REQ_StaminaRateMult_bonus_highlight	Your stamina regeneration is governed only by your stamina.
$REQ_StaminaRateMult_highlight	With a high stamina regeneration you require less time to catch your breath and recover from physical stress. (The value is given in percent of your current maximum stamina.)
$REQ_TimesShouted	understanding from thu'um usage
$REQ_TimesShouted_highlight	Unleashing the power of the thu'um and becoming familiar with its potence will sharpen your rhetoric skills with the draconic language. The displayed value shows the percentage reduction of the time you need to recover between two consecutive shouts.
$REQ_TwoHandedPowerMod	two-handed weapons
$REQ_TwoHandedPowerMod_highlight	Your efficiency with two-handed weapons is determined primarily by your health, with a small contribution from your stamina.
$REQ_UnarmedDamage	hand-to-hand strength
$REQ_UnarmedDamage_highlight	The strength of your fist punches is determined in equal parts by your health and stamina.
$REQ_WordsLearned	understanding from known words
$REQ_WordsLearned_highlight	Once you have acquired a basic vocabulary, your thu'um will become more and more powerful the more words you learn from the draconic language. The displayed value shows the percentage reduction of the time you need to recover between two consecutive shouts.
$REQ_WordsUnlocked	understanding from mastered words
$REQ_WordsUnlocked_highlight	Reflecting on the deeper meaning of the individual words of the thu'um is essential if you want to master this power. The displayed value shows the percentage reduction of the time you need to recover between two consecutive shouts.
$REQ_Atmosphere_KillmoveHealthThreshold	Killmove health threshold
$REQ_Atmosphere_KillmoveHealthThreshold_highlight	This defines how hard a target must be hit before a melee killmove is allowed. The default value allows killmoves when the target is in the rapid heartbeat stage. Setting this to 0% will disable melee killmoves.
$REQ_Atmosphere_KillmoveHealthThreshold_slider	{0}%
$REQ_cat_skill_expertise	Secondary Skill Stats
$REQ_cat_skill_expertise_header	Secondary stats for your skills
$REQ_expertise_header_combat	Combat Skills
$REQ_expertise_header_rogue	Rogue Skills
$REQ_expertise_onehanded	One-Handed Armor Penetration
$REQ_expertise_twohanded	Two-Handed Armor Penetration
$REQ_expertise_marksman	Marksman  Armor Penetration
$REQ_expertise_lockpicking	Lockpicking Expertise
$REQ_expertise_onehanded_highlight	A detailed explanation of the armor penetration system can be found in the ingame help menu.
$REQ_expertise_twohanded_highlight	A detailed explanation of the armor penetration system can be found in the ingame help menu.
$REQ_expertise_marksman_highlight	A detailed explanation of the armor penetration system can be found in the ingame help menu.
$REQ_expertise_lockpicking_highlight	A detailed explanation of the lockpicking system can be found in the ingame help menu.
